So we are going to be creating our first primary standard DNS zone.
So to create this standard DNS zone, what you need to do is, on your domain name does
a seven name, here we have for lookup zone, so you don't need to right click and then click
new zone.
On here it says welcome to the new zone with our latest click next and you can see we have
different options.
We have our primary zone, second reason, stop zone and at this moment you want to create
a primary zone.
And you can see we have the option called store the zone in active directory, see available
only to the DNS server is a rightable domain controller.
But since we are going to be creating it just a standard DNS primary zone, we don't want to
store this in our active directory at this moment.
So we need to uncheck this, uncheck the storage zone in active directory and then click
next.
Here you need to give your zone a name, so let me just call this the kill of the shot of
the call, blah blah.
Then we are going to call this the standard zone, we are going to call it zone one.
So let's just click next, and you can see this is creating new file with a file name.
Here you see the file and now we created a little bit of DNS, but you guys will use the
system file, but we just go to create a new one, but mind you I'm giving actually the
name because this is actually for, it's not actually for a production, this is just for
a demo.
So this is not in the production environment, definitely want to give a more, more name
that's compliant with the policy of your company, so let's just click next.
And it says here you can see says allow both non secure and secure dynamic updates, dynamic
update of the social code are accepted from any client or do not allow the dynamic update.
So what is actually dynamic update, dynamic, what's that dynamic update, dynamic DNS
of updating allows client to create an delete DNS record in a particular zone.
So in a DS, if you're environment, this is useful, so clients with changing IP addresses
can update zone addresses without the local DNS server.
So just imagine, without the dynamic update administrator, we need to update each client
device machine manually, which is almost impossible if you are working in the medium of
very large environments.
So let's move on, let's just select the allow both non secure and secure dynamic update
and then click next, and there you can see we're going to actually check our summary
if everything is complete.
So let's go back again and then click finish.
So for this zone as we created, you can see our zone we just created, and you can see
we have two records with the S O A and the name server record.
So if I write, click and then click properties, here you can see it says it's a totally
primary, and also the dynamic update you can see is non secure and also secure.
And if I click that you can see we have those one contract into non, we'll leave it for that.
And also lastly, you can see since replication is not an actually directory integrated zone.